# Mihir Mirchandani

650-526-8695 | mihir.mirchandani@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/mihir-mirchandani/

### **Profile**

Sophomore Computer Science and Data Science student at UC Berkeley with a proven aptitude for Software Engineering, Data Science, and Product Management. Resilient problem solver that is always working on technical, social impact projects. Team player with excellent communication skills and experience. Driven learner that spearheads initiative and reform.

### **Education**

Los Altos High School - GPA: 3.95 and 4.52, graduated with honors and distinction! UC Berkeley (Class of 2023) - Computer Science B.A. | Data Science B.A. Relevant Coursework: Electrical Engineering, Circuits, Data Structures, and Algorithms

## **Scholarships and Awards**

UC Berkeley SEED's STEM equity finalist, Microsoft Student Learn Alpha Certificate, 2021 Employee Resource Group STEM Scholarships, Honors Student, Bilingual Status (English & Spanish), AP Scholar with Honor, 3 President's Volunteer Service Awards (Gold, Silver, and Bronze), Outstanding Student Award in Science, Golden State Seal Merit Diploma, Academic Scholar, California Scholarship Federation Gold Seal Life Member and Sealbearer.

### Skills

Programming Languages: Java, Python, SQL, JavaScript Software: Tableau, Eclipse, IntelliJ, Atom, Sublime, VSC, vim, Jupyter Notebooks Data Science Libraries: NumPy, Pandas, PyTorch, TensorFlow, BeautifulSoup4, scikit-learn Technologies: Git, JUnit, Excel, Word, PowerPoint, OneNote, Zoom, Slack

## **Certifications and Projects**

- *Google* Data Analytics Professional Certificate, *IBM* Data Science, *Stanford* Introduction to Statistics, *Udemy* Python Projects and Django Web Development, *Google* IT Automation with Python Professional Certificate, *UC San Diego* Data Structures and Algorithms, and *University of Michigan* Python For Everybody Specialization.
- Ultra Watch: Engineered a device to help the blind navigate their surroundings using ultrasonic sensors, piezoelectric buzzers, and an Arduino.
- Value Meal Stocks: designed a website for my Microeconomics teacher to share the approximations of stock value based on accounting factors such as enterprise value, sales, interest rates, and book value to intrinsically value a company. (2020 Summer Project)
- Linux System-Administration Project, Open Computing Facility at UC Berkeley. Logging web servers for quick statistics on performance, display web data analytics. (Fall 2021 Project)

## **Work Experience**

Microsoft - Student Learn Ambassador (October 2021 - Present)

❖ I help students in my local community learn how to code and develop technical skills using lectures. I make such an impact along with a team of dedicated and resilient engineers to be campus leaders in our respective universities and to be active in our online communities.

AT&T - Summer Extern (May 2021 - August 2021)

❖ I had the privilege of virtually meeting many famous engineers, such as Sal Khan, Founder of Khan Academy, and seeing what the jobs of engineers look like across the spectrum from Project Management to Machine Learning Engineering.

NWF Strategies - Software Engineer Intern (May 2021 - August 2021)

❖ I work on the development of software to enhance reporting to political campaigns in areas such as marketing and funding. I also use analytics to support data-driven reporting. On the side, I help make websites and research municipal campaigns with local governments for NWF Strategies.

Code Ninjas - Computer Science Instructor (April 2021 - August 2021)

❖ Taught students aged 9 - 14 to learn essential computer science concepts in Python, Java, JavaScript, Unity, and C#. Was responsible for Game Development with Roblox and Minecraft Workshops and Camps. Oversaw program curriculums and led instruction.

Chess With Mihir - CEO and Founder (July 2018 - Present)

❖ Taught chess for 6 years, founded Chess With Mihir after receiving the President's Volunteer Service Awards, Rated top 10% in the country, Chess Club President in middle and high school, directed teams to prepare for championship and use an analytical mind

YouTube Channel (Jan 2012 - Present)

❖ I am an avid poster on YouTube and I am a big fan of sharing CS projects, chess tutorials, coding tutorials and more! I believe that YouTube has helped me develop excellent interpersonal skills as I have rehearsed with several people for presentations and reports LAHS Hacks - Tech Team/Organizer (Aug 2020 - June 2021)

Organized the fourth largest high school hackathon recently, worked alongside resilient SWEs to facilitate attendance, project submission, and administrative panels. Also helped develop Discord Bot to virtually assist/interact with participants

Science Nation - Director of Sales and Finance (Aug 2020 - June 2021)

Working alongside a group of Directors to ensure that everyone has equal opportunity in technology, Orchestrated all fundraising for NPOs like human-I-T that bring WiFi and revitalized computers for children across the country. Also helped tutor in digital literacy

Summer Research Project Intern- High School Researcher (June 2020 - Aug 2020)

❖ Implemented python scripts to web scrape and data mine finance websites, and then store data on CSVs. After logging each metric, an additional script was used to crunch the data using python libraries. The crunched data was then sent to my Raspberry Pi where a web server would log that data and include it on a dynamic website using Django Frameworks, HTML, CSS, and JS

Tutree - Intern (Jan 2020 - June 2020)

Grew a startup to teach college-level math with development teams in India to build Ambassador Program, growing and networking with students